<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entry type="method" name="load" return="jQuery" deprecated="1.8">
  <title>.load()</title>
  <desc>Bind an event handler to the "load" JavaScript event.</desc>
  <signature>
    <added>1.0</added>
    <argument name="handler" type="Function">
      <desc>A function to execute when the event is triggered.</desc>
      <argument name="eventObject" type="Event" />
    </argument>
  </signature>
  <signature>
    <added>1.4.3</added>
    <argument name="eventData" type="Anything" optional="true">
      <desc>An object containing data that will be passed to the event handler.</desc>
    </argument>
    <argument name="handler" type="Function">
      <desc>A function to execute each time the event is triggered.</desc>
      <argument name="eventObject" type="Event" />
    </argument>
  </signature>
  <longdesc>
    <p>This method is a shortcut for <code>.on( "load", handler )</code>.</p>
    <p>The <code>load</code> event is sent to an element when it and all sub-elements have been completely loaded. This event can be sent to any element associated with a URL: images, scripts, frames, iframes, and the <code>window</code> object.</p>
    <p>For example, consider a page with an iframe:</p>
    <pre><code>
&lt;iframe src="/my-beautiful-widget.html" id="widget"&gt;
    </code></pre>
    <p>The event handler can be bound to the iframe:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( "#widget" ).load(function() {
  // Handler for .load() called.
});
    </code></pre>
    <p>As soon as the iframe has been loaded, the handler is called.</p>
    <div class="warning">
      <p>The Ajax module also has a method named <code><a href="/load/">.load()</a></code>. Which one is fired depends on the set of arguments passed.</p>
    </div>
    <div class="warning">
      <p>
        <b>Caveats of the <code>load</code> event when used with images</b>
        <p>A common challenge developers attempt to solve using the <code>.load()</code> shortcut is to execute a function when an image (or collection of images) have completely loaded. There are several known caveats with this that should be noted. These are:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>It doesn't work consistently nor reliably cross-browser</li>
          <li>It doesn't fire correctly in WebKit if the image src is set to the same src as before</li>
          <li>It doesn't correctly bubble up the DOM tree</li>
          <li>Can cease to fire for images that already live in the browser's cache</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </div>
    <div class="warning">
      <p><strong>Note:</strong> The <code>.live()</code> and <code>.delegate()</code> methods cannot be used to detect the <code>load</code> event of an iframe. The load event does not correctly bubble up the parent document and the <code>event.target</code> isn't set by Firefox, IE9 or Chrome, which is required to do event delegation.</p>
    </div>
  </longdesc>
  <example>
    <desc>Run a function when the page is fully loaded including graphics and other resources.</desc>
    <code><![CDATA[
$( window ).load(function() {
  // Run code
});
]]></code>
  </example>
  <example>
        <desc>Add the class bigImg to each image with height greater than 100 on load, implementing a partial workaround for image-loading issues.</desc>
        <code><![CDATA[
var setBigClass = function( img ) {
  if ( $( img ).height() > 100 ) {
    $( img ).addClass( "bigImg" );
  }
};

$( "img.userIcon" ).each(function() {
  var src = this.src;
  var blank = "data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///ywAAAAAAQABAAACAUwAOw==";

  // IE sets a "complete" property on already-loaded images
  if ( this.complete ) {
    setBigClass( this );
  } else {
    $( this ).load( setBigClass );

    // Avoid Webkit bug by quickly swapping src back and forth
    this.src = blank;
    this.src = src;
  }
});
]]></code>
  </example>
  <category slug="events/document-loading"/>
  <category slug="version/1.0"/>
  <category slug="version/1.4.3"/>
  <category slug="deprecated/deprecated-1.8"/>
</entry>
